[
  {
    "question": "What is the superorder that mantises are a part of?",
    "answer": "Dictyoptera",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Mantis"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many segments does an arthropod's body have?",
    "answer": "Arthropods have segmented bodies.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Arthropod"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the gestation period of a bobcat?",
    "answer": "about two months",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Bobcat"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest city in New Zealand?",
    "answer": "Auckland",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/New_Zealand"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term 'Rosetta Stone' now used to refer to?",
    "answer": "The term 'Rosetta Stone' is now used to refer to the essential clue to a new field of knowledge.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Rosetta_Stone"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many plays did William Shakespeare write?",
    "answer": "He wrote 39 plays.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/William_Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "question": "What caused the explosion that vented the contents of the SM's oxygen tanks to space?",
    "answer": "A routine stir of an oxygen tank ignited damaged wire insulation inside it.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Apollo_13"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many decades did Michael Jackson's career span?",
    "answer": "Four decades.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Michael_Jackson"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is horizontal gene transfer?",
    "answer": "The transfer of genes between organisms.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Virus"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many varieties of Arabic does the International Organization for Standardization assign language codes to?",
    "answer": "33",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Arabic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a midfielder in association football?",
    "answer": "A midfielder is an outfield position in association football.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Midfielder"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the origin of termites?",
    "answer": "Termites diverged from cockroaches during the Late Jurassic.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Termite"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Global Financial Centres Index?",
    "answer": "The Global Financial Centres Index (GFCI) is a ranking of the competitiveness of financial centres.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Hong_Kong"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the raccoon's scientific name?",
    "answer": "Procyon lotor",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Raccoon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary cause of decline for lion populations?",
    "answer": "Habitat loss and conflicts with humans are the greatest causes for concern.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Lion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the class of animals to which all living amphibians belong?",
    "answer": "Lissamphibia",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Amphibian"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many provinces does Argentina have?",
    "answer": "Twenty-three",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Argentina"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first drummer for the Beatles?",
    "answer": "Pete Best",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/The_Beatles"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of the United States?",
    "answer": "Washington, D.C.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Hippopotamus"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gastropods are there in the world?",
    "answer": "It is estimated that there are approximately 80,000 species of gastropods.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Gastropoda"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the American music and entertainment magazine that provides music charts, news, video, opinion, reviews, events, and style related to the music industry?",
    "answer": "Billboard",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Billboard_(magazine)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average African American of West/Central African with some European descent?",
    "answer": "Most African Americans are descendants of enslaved people within the boundaries of the present United States.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/African_Americans"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary reason for the decline in frog populations?",
    "answer": "The primary reason for the decline in frog populations is the emergence of a fungal disease called chytridiomycosis.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Frog"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bat species are there in the world?",
    "answer": "Over 1,400",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Bat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first owner of Anfield?",
    "answer": "Everton",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Anfield"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which international organizations is Canada a part of?",
    "answer": "Canada is a part of the United Nations, NATO, the G7, the Group of Ten, the G20, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), the World Trade Organization (WTO), the Commonwealth of Nations, the Arctic Council, the Organisation internationale de la Francophonie, the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum, and the Organization of American States.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Canada"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first consumer video game?",
    "answer": "The first consumer video game was the arcade video game Computer Space in 1971.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Video_game"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tallest living bird?",
    "answer": "The emu.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Emu"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest economy in Europe?",
    "answer": "Germany",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Germany"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a wiki?",
    "answer": "A wiki is an online hypertext publication collaboratively edited and managed by its own audience, using a web browser.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Wiki"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the scientific study of naming, defining, and classifying groups of biological organisms based on shared characteristics?",
    "answer": "Taxonomy",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Taxonomy_(biology)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the standard vocabulary for human anatomy?",
    "answer": "Terminologia Anatomica",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Anatomical_terms_of_location"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the dominant process that a star uses to generate energy?",
    "answer": "The dominant process that a star uses to generate energy is nuclear fusion.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Main_sequence"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the major classes of organic molecules that contain oxygen atoms?",
    "answer": "Proteins, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, and fats.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Oxygen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of the United States?",
    "answer": "Washington, D.C.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/List_of_states_and_territories_of_the_United_States"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary food source of cougars?",
    "answer": "Ungulates, particularly deer.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Cougar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the Arthurian legend originate?",
    "answer": "Geoffrey's version of events often served as the starting point for later stories.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/King_Arthur"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of ants have been classified?",
    "answer": "More than 13,800 of an estimated total of 22,000 species have been classified.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Ant"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of moth are there?",
    "answer": "There are thought to be approximately 160,000 species of moth.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Moth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the immediate treatment for a suspected MI?",
    "answer": "Aspirin",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Myocardial_infarction"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was King of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland and King of Hanover from the death of his father, King George III, on 29 January 1820, until his own death ten years later?",
    "answer": "George IV",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/George_IV"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many fungal species have been described?",
    "answer": "148,000",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Fungus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the group that the noble gases are in for the first six periods of the periodic table?",
    "answer": "Group 18",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Noble_gas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the head of the Catholic Church?",
    "answer": "The pope.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Catholic_Church"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the title that Diocletian took on?",
    "answer": "Diocletian took on the title \"dominus noster\" (our lord).",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/List_of_Roman_emperors"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many buildings were in the original World Trade Center complex?",
    "answer": "Seven",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/World_Trade_Center_(1973\u20132001)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first to reach the geographic South Pole?",
    "answer": "Norwegian explorers",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Antarctica"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invented the Watt steam engine?",
    "answer": "James Watt",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Birmingham"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some examples of enzymes being used commercially?",
    "answer": "Examples of enzymes being used commercially are in the synthesis of antibiotics and in some household products.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Enzyme"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the longest extant millipede species?",
    "answer": "The giant African millipede (Archispirostreptus gigas)",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Millipede"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the xiuhpohualli?",
    "answer": "The xiuhpohualli is the calendric system of a xiuhpohualli of 365\u00a0days intercalated with a tonalpohualli of 260\u00a0days.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Aztecs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the GDP of the United States?",
    "answer": "The United States has a GDP of approximately $20.5 trillion.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/United_States"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the market share of Microsoft Windows?",
    "answer": "74.99%",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Operating_system"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of Australia?",
    "answer": "Perth",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Perth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of the United States?",
    "answer": "Washington, D.C.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Shiva"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of the United States?",
    "answer": "Washington, D.C.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Bird"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many legs does an adult arachnid have?",
    "answer": "8",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Arachnid"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary material of a turtle's shell?",
    "answer": "Bone",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Turtle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main forms of precipitation?",
    "answer": "The main forms of precipitation include drizzle, rain, sleet, snow, ice pellets, graupel and hail.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Precipitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the clade Mandibulata?",
    "answer": "The clade Mandibulata is a group of animals which includes such animals as decapods, seed shrimp, branchiopods, fish lice, krill, remipedes, isopods, barnacles, copepods, amphipods and mantis shrimp.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Crustacean"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the GDP of London?",
    "answer": "\u20ac801.66 billion",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/London"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is binomial nomenclature?",
    "answer": "Binomial nomenclature is a formal system of naming species of living things by giving each a name composed of two parts, both of which use Latin grammatical forms.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Binomial_nomenclature"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many films did Elvis Presley make in the 1960s?",
    "answer": "Elvis Presley made 9 films in the 1960s.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Elvis_Presley"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the national animal of India, Bangladesh, Malaysia and South Korea?",
    "answer": "The tiger.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Tiger"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many individuals have served as president of the United States?",
    "answer": "45",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/President_of_the_United_States"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did sponsors' logos begin to appear on football shirts?",
    "answer": "In the 20th century.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Kit_(association_football)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the NFL founded?",
    "answer": "1920",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/National_Football_League"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many beetle species are used as food?",
    "answer": "Over 300 beetle species are used as food.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Beetle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the study of animals called?",
    "answer": "Zoology",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Animal"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many locally elected officials govern the district?",
    "answer": "One mayor and thirteen council members.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Washington,_D.C."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do males establish social hierarchies among giraffes?",
    "answer": "Males establish social hierarchies among giraffes through \"necking\", combat bouts where the neck is used as a weapon.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Giraffe"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the only extant member of the genus Homo?",
    "answer": "Homo sapiens",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Human"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long can tarantulas and other mygalomorph spiders live?",
    "answer": "Up to 25 years in captivity.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Spider"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Australia's population?",
    "answer": "Australia's population is nearly 26 million.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Australia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the major insect order Diptera?",
    "answer": "Flies are important pollinators, second only to the bees and their Hymenopteran relatives.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Fly"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the evidence of Sanskrit in India?",
    "answer": "The hymns of the Rigveda.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/India"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the Hoover Dam completed?",
    "answer": "March 1, 1936",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Hoover_Dam"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of Canada?",
    "answer": "Ottawa",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Canadians"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most populous incorporated place in the United States?",
    "answer": "New York City",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/List_of_United_States_cities_by_population"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can too much or too little of a vitamin lead to?",
    "answer": "Clinically significant illness.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Vitamin"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Grammy Awards has Dylan won?",
    "answer": "10",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Bob_Dylan"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Gospels are there in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Four",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Jesus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of Scotland?",
    "answer": "Edinburgh",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Charles_Darwin"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long was Elizabeth II's reign?",
    "answer": "70 years and 214 days",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Elizabeth_II"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was one of the leaders of the 1963 March on Washington?",
    "answer": "Martin Luther King, Jr.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Martin_Luther_King_Jr."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many national parks are designated UNESCO Biosphere Reserves?",
    "answer": "21",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/List_of_national_parks_of_the_United_States"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the abbreviation for Linnaeus?",
    "answer": "L.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Carl_Linnaeus"
  },
  {
    "question": "How are bivalves used in the biocontrol of pollution?",
    "answer": "Bivalves are used in the biocontrol of pollution by filtering water and removing pollutants.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Bivalvia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Marxism?",
    "answer": "Marxism is a social, political, and economic theory originated by Karl Marx, which focuses on the struggle between capitalists and the working class.",
    "reference": "wiki_100/A/Karl_Marx"
  }
]
